all right dude now now I get out the you
know that Meme where it's like that guy
in front of the board with a bunch of
lines on it and like uh the connection
and just here we go you know yeah that's
honestly a little bit how I think most
people view uh uh oo so we'll see I
thought you were going to say
me best Ving when you can just you know
critical thing right
[Music]
dude Al righty man fresh out of the
vision meeting for crit digital and uh
into the podcast I'm feeling pretty hype
about the direction and everything for
the Pod yeah dude I mean the one big
takeaway that we can you know tell the
the listeners about is that our goal is
to continue to help them succeed or to
be their Advocate or whatever want to
call it right there's a bunch of
different ways we could say it but we
want to empower the hackers yeah I think
that's the overall vision for for the
the Discord community and and really you
know the podcast as a as a sub piece of
that but uh as as a whole you know any
way that we can support the community
whether it be with uh Recon data with
techniques with like you know like one
of the things we do with the full-time
Hunters Guild is like help people gauge
how burnt out they're getting and try to
avoid burnout um yeah that I think
that's the I think that's the vision
long term and I think it's a good good
one man I think it's a good one yeah I
think so too completely underserved yeah
we we've we've got a lot and not a lot
of time so uh let's let's jump right
into it you want me to take the first
one yeah let's do it all right let's
jump into the news um first one that
popped up uh that I that I thought was
really interesting is this uh post from
nc.zip uh that's the that's the domain
um and it's the Dom purify 3.2 bypass uh
and I will go ahead and share my screen
this time so let me go ahead and do that
um and this one was a really interesting
D purify bypass whenever there's a a
specific uh you know a default
configuration D purified bypass you
definitely want to pay attention to it
um so I read this one through and man
you know look how short this article is
yeah it's super short um and and like
whenever you can condense something so
complex as a down purify bypass down to
something so so simple it's it's really
beautiful and the main takeaway for me
for this one was that uh there is not
a um sort of agreed upon uh definition
for a comment between Dum purify and the
browser and that's what they were able
to to exploit um the according to the
what WG uh HTML spec uh typically you
know you're supposed to start your
comments with uh you know angle bracket
exclamation point-- and HTML but there's
also a uh sort of accommodation made for
forgetting the dash dash so it's just
angle bracket exclamation point and the
browser perceived that as a comment but
Dom purify didn't and then using that
they were able to create a mutation xss
which bypass D purifies uh default
filters yeah so in general I think that
you know I think they even say that
there's a pattern of them being similar
like with the latest few bypasses that
have been found but and that makes total
sense to me like it's so clear to most
people when there's um a specific you
know xss that's trying to be popped
whether it's image source or whether
it's alert or whether whatever but like
the issue is that all of these parsers
have to like be able to kind of trust
what's inside of a comment and so
attacking what is a comment actually oh
man what's his name anyways there was a
yeah healthy Outlet you remember Ryan
ryx he he did a lot with this uh like
similar not with not with Dum purify but
he did a lot with um looking for
bypasses looking for xss in the
different ways that comments are handled
in what you see is what you get editors
and I know that he U was able to find a
lot of different vulnerabilities I think
he even did a few talks in Canada on
this specific topic and so yeah I think
that looking in the ways that comments
are handled in this and in other
applications is a really great area for
research yeah 100% and then and then you
know just kind of building on top of
that he there was there was one other
piece there which was this piece about
um a very liberal template injection
sanitization that was happening in
inside of uh D purify which was just
essentially taking everything um that
inside of uh the template sort of
injection flow and and removing it um
resulted in in him being able to pull
off the full flow and then you know I
think one of the things that he mentions
in this article as well is that he was
able to reduce it just to a couple
Primitives you know he's like okay if we
have a way to smuggle in you know and
cause this difference then you know we
can use one of the more common um
mutation xss formats and he he even
cites this guy uh Yaniv niri sorry
that's going to be a that's a hard name
to pronounce um you know with with that
actual mutation xss piece so I think if
you can reduce this down to Primitives
it gets much easier and then you can
reuse components from other bypasses as
well um so you're not just Reinventing
the wheel yeah I know I'm always
mentioning AI but I think that it's kind
of interesting you could probably give
all this data from these two blog posts
to you know a model especially one of
the smarter ones like you know the 03
that got released and uh probably
generate a bunch of potential payloads
like you know generate hundreds or
thousands of them and then kind of run
it automatically through to find another
bypass potentially yeah absolutely
that's definitely possible all right
what what do you have on your list next
yeah I guess I'll transition straight
into that um you know 03 mini and 03
mini High dropped this last week um from
a hacking perspective I think it's going
to be the best um specifically I think I
messag you because I think yeah if you
think about like what we do especially
when we're hacking on something we try
something as hackers right we try
something we get a different error we
try something else we get a different
error we try something get closer and
closer to the output and I think in
general these kind of like one shot with
Noth thinking uh models that have been
used you know in the past that we've all
been using or like can be really really
smart but ultimately they can't get
there to the same process of this like
kind of deep level of expertise and like
kind of playing with it and so I think
uh it would not surprise me my intuition
says that if you were testing something
and like you're testing a vulnerability
and you're getting a verbose Air at the
very least those are going to be the
easiest to work with of course and you
you can copy and paste out all your
payloads and all the errors and and walk
it through like what your thought
process is and say like hey continue my
thought process give me a bunch of other
payloads to try um and if you convince
it to to do that without complaining
about security or safety issues my
intuition is that these are going to be
like the the in fact I saw this um tweet
from some highlevel people uh what's his
name Jason Zoo it's Jason Z hu he's like
one of the best um the most prolific
like YouTubers that like help you become
like an AI engineer and build stuff with
AI he was saying that in his test he's
been testing it for the last you know a
couple days that um 03 mini is by far
the best at agentic workflows and so I
think so yeah I mean I don't know I
message you about it because I think we
should add it to shift I think it'd be
really cool if it took like all of the
past replay diffs in a replay like
because obviously when you're replay or
repeater and you're making small itative
changes that's a good idea you didn't
listen to my audio message Justin fine
I'll say it again here sorry no you're
fine I think we need like a downshift
button or something and shift where on a
replay tab it does a diff of the like
the last 10 um histories of like you
know all the iterations all the things
you tried in that replay Tab and it
sends the initial request and then like
the diff with the response the diff with
the response the diff with the response
and so you know especially if you're
getting like forbose error messages or
if it's um sanitizing some xss or you
know you're getting something or
something like that yeah exactly then
it'd be really interesting to to um take
that and then hand that off to a model
and be like hey continue this train of
thought and give me a bunch of examples
of things to try that's a good way of
structuring yeah that that like you kind
of utilize its ability to continue on a
trend that it's already seen that's
that's a good point so for O3 mini is it
like because I know one of the reasons
we use the anthropic models and and and
even some of the the Google models is
that they're fast and they're cheap and
they're smart you know like you got kind
of got that Trifecta right and you know
maybe the the f fter and cheaper models
are a little bit less smart but if they
still accomplish your purpose or you can
get it across with good prompt
engineering what you want to do
yeah it still works well so what is what
does o03 mini sort of land on in that in
that um so it does it uses thinking
tokens on the back end so it's not going
to be instant inference but um if you
say like um
brainstorm 10 new potential you know xss
patterns uh based on this Dawn purify
bypass let's just do the exact let's
just do the example we just talked about
right and go now now I'm just going to
paste in the the content of these two
blogs um and so it it probably is going
to reject me because I haven't said like
I'm an ethical researcher doing for
things but you can just see the speed
here so I hit enter you know it's
thinking it's navigating the boundaries
that it has for web security noting this
request nature and focusing on not the
you know vulnerabilities sorry it says
refusal as a yeah and and then it
rejected but yeah so that's the speed so
you know it's not instant it's not but
it's pretty Snappy yeah it's not going
to take more than you know at least with
mini with high I think it can go for you
know 30 seconds so but it's not like
it's not like 01 Pro which is going to
think for you know 10 minutes so you can
actually build mini into applications
without too much of an issue do you pay
you you do pay $200 a month for the pro
man that's so actually I reached out to
them and just asked if I could have a
month to test with but I will to pay
when it RS but no I didn't actually pay
for this one yeah yeah yeah they should
give it to the researchers for free man
I think so to it's on bug crowd right
any bug crowd staff out there listening
to this come on you guys got to make
that happen that would be that'd be
amazing if you you like reached out to
the top researchers and gave them um 01
uh or I guess what is it like uh yeah
it's called Pro or something Pro yeah
Pro that's it that'd be pretty pretty
rad um all right any anything else on
that or should I hop over to
the too long yeah you're good
um next item in the news was uh the live
chat blog number two from Mr Rohan over
here at ofon security uh he's a homie
he's a he was a a regular in the live
hacking event scene and it's just such a
creative hacker I love I love reading
any of his writeups um and so this one's
this one's a good one to check out
especially for for those of you guys
that are a little bit um not sure how to
attack chat related Bots um he kind of
gives a good write up of his approach
not just the the result of the
vulnerability and uh he talks about some
of the authentication mechanisms that
were used um in in this specific uh
write up uh so definitely a good just
sort of conceptual uh approach um and
and then he he highlights just the main
takeaway from me here was just look at
how these things are doing
authentication don't just like sub in
the IDS and and look for idor related
stuff but also look at how they're doing
authentication and try to identify some
end points maybe even from Brew forcing
or from hacker tuition where you might
be able to uh access uh like a list of
of threads is what they're called in the
specific write up like a list of chats
that have been had um and try to cross
that sort of individual user um uh line
especially when the authentication is
specifically you know in this scenario
it's key based uh it just was in the
JavaScript so it's not differentiated
per user as strongly yeah so I I have a
couple different thoughts here one is
especially on what you just said I have
found myself doing that more uh lately
and it's been so beneficial it's led to
multiple vulnerabilities like um and
specifically what I mean is like
following that flow of like Hey how do I
actually get off on this how does this
where does this off actually come from
and I think in the past it felt
intimidating one because I think off
stuff kind of feels a little bit
difficult it's not it's not really that
complicated when you start looking at it
and then the other thing is I think that
I didn't know how to do it because he
gets lost in all the other requests and
kind of like mapping it in bar parido is
like not trivial and so what I found
that really helps is just working
backwards and I'll do specific string
searches this might be hard and BT but
it's really easy and kaido basically if
I have some bear token I'll copy and
paste that bear token into the HTP ql
bar at the top of HTP history with
quotes around it so I don't have to like
deal with any HTP ql and then see where
and then like see where it gets set and
then I'll see what got passed to that
it's like did my credentials get pass to
that or was it a token or was it an O
code whatever just look at the flow that
happened well then I searched for that
string right and then I go to that
request and sometimes you have to step
back two or three different requests but
often you'll be like oh all it took to
generate this was the my username right
and on each of those steps you can try
to hack them too right so like if it's
on the username and password want I just
remove the password and see if it can
just authenticate you if you just use
the email right that's pretty rare these
days but I think you can do that saw
though I mentioned that at my Defcon
talk this year was like one of the
highest paid bugs I've ever had was
there was like I could just pass
password is null into this like really
uh high security system and it just let
me in and I'm like this is insane yeah
definitely always try I mean drop the
key completely or try to pass all or um
yeah kind of you can do that sometimes
with Json objects with like not a number
if it requires an integer and stuff
there's kind of some funny things you
can do there but then the other thing I
was going to say which you didn't call
it out directly but the key
vulnerability in this blog post for
anyone who doesn't go and read it is
that they were using the client key as
the secret key and for some reason I
think just third parties and widgets and
stuff are so much more prone to do stuff
like this because it's just complicated
to figure out off and so I think
developers think ah if it's just some
embedded function that's deep inside of
this minifi JavaScript you know if we do
something slightly you know bad practice
it's fine No One's Gonna find it or look
at
it yeah yeah I think those those are
really really and you kind of have to
dive a little bit deep into the
architecture of these plugins to sort of
identify it right um but that that point
that they were using um that they were
leaking the the the secret key uh
absolutely relevant and we see that you
know that's why I think stripe does the
thing where they have like PK uncore and
skore right and it makes it really easy
if you to understand oh this is a secret
key or this is a public key um but but
some of the other providers don't do
that as clearly so making sure you check
the permissions on your specific key is
the best way to identify whether these
sort of vulnerabilities are going to
come up and for that you got to read the
docs and figure out what the what the
API request looks like yeah and another
thing on this uh post which is not
really relevant to the content of it but
whenever I saw this in there from ran or
Roan as some people call him um it's
just like my heart just got warm I feel
like it's really uh interesting but in
the bug Bounty space I feel like there's
just a stronger sense of camaraderie or
Community it's like you all really do
want to support each other and so as
soon as you saw this link in the news I
was like oh man love that guy I ran I
ran into him at bsides SF like last year
and hadn't seen each other or speak
spoken to each other in years and we
just immediately hit it off again yeah
dude
wonderful member of the community I I
have a lot of lot of respect for him and
his techniques you know just very
creative hacker I think is the big thing
that just sort of stands out um with
with him for me and I I there's a
specific private program we'll bleep it
but it's and he's just been like
crushing it on them for for years which
is just so uh every time I go to that
program I look at the activity I'm like
yep still popping 5Ks you know on the R
so pretty rad to see yeah so I have
three different
Discord Community related uh news items
I'll say my uh really important I'll say
my really important one first before I
get to the other smaller ones so the
really important one is that we put
Emojis next to every channel and Justin
hated it so we rolled it back so now
they're on each category which really
does help when I'm scrolling through
like just being able to see the colors
at the category level to know like oh
critical thinkers is in here it helps so
much yeah dude I I don't know man I'm
sorry and I feel bad for Yugi as well
cuz I was like Yugi let's you know let's
try to spice it up a little bit cuz I
cuz the reason I said that is I was like
you know looking at our Discord
Community actually joined our Discord
Community as a as a different like as a
a test user just to see what the flow
looked like and I was like a this looks
a little Bland you know when I don't
have all of the the you know cies to CH
exactly and the critical thinkers
channels and supporter channels so um I
was like a let's spice it up a little
bit and then Yugi's like leave it to me
you know say less and and he adds emojis
and I'm like I regret I regret it I
can't do this it it's driving me nuts
you know and we pulled the community and
it was pretty split you know everybody
was like yeah you know there was some a
lot of people in the hate it a lot of
people in the love it and then there was
a bunch of middle so it's like I don't
know but I think the the categories is a
nice a nice medium nice yeah so uh I'll
jump straight to one of these other ones
I uh you probably you friended people
probably thought this was super easy but
there was a critical thinker named Arya
who said they ran into a snack with
their post based xss the payload had to
be in the body as is with no key it
could not be like name value had to be
just value sure and so then Thatcher's
gold popped in with a awesome exploit
let me see if I can share I can probably
just share that do you know if when you
share um if you're zoomed in it shows
the zoomed in view or it shows the whole
thing it should okay cool I don't want
to share our whole doc we can always
just block it out if we need to yeah no
this is a good this is a good trick you
know specifically pertaining to text
plane uh if if your target will take
text plane as the content type there's a
lot of weird stuff you can do yeah so
this is the this is the working exploit
so it's form action endpoint method post
with the encoding type text plane and
then the the name is this but the value
is just empty string so it doesn't
actually set that so um it ends up
properly setting it exactly like this
which is what he needed um which is
pretty sweet I think that should give
you a little bit of a a trailing equal
sign too but one of the things that we
we do with that is often is we'll use it
as like an attribute um in a in an xss
payload so like image
you know you got to provide like Source
equals X or whatever so there's an equal
sign in that you can embed in there and
then you can kind of kind of push it
through oh yeah they did say at the
bottom there get you a trailing equal
sign but is that an issue and it was not
an issue that ended up working for him
so pretty sweet pretty perfect man yeah
the Cent there's a lot of client side
stuff that we we do a lot of client side
debugging that happens in the critical
thinkers chat where people are like ah
I've almost got this xss and you know
someone pops in and be like yeah just
tweak it like this and you're good to go
yeah you know so and whenever whenever I
see that my heart gets War I'm like yes
like we just we just paid for our
subscription you know we just added the
value for them for years years exactly
exactly off of that one that one Bounty
yeah yeah no so that that that's always
cool to see um I just got two little
little quick ones uh one was that
there's this really awesome hacker I
don't know that you've like for some
reason this guy was not on my radar very
much but it's endev TK oh yeah I've been
following him for a long time yeah yeah
I just started following recently but or
maybe was following him but I wasn't you
know I just didn't have it in my head
but he's uh one of the big hackers on on
Google and I think we've actually even
covered some of his stuff on the Pod
here before um and just has a wealth of
knowledge about Google stuff as I'm sort
of getting a little bit more into the
Google ecosystem that he shared which
was which was very kind yeah and then um
and then also just recently released a
uh post logger Chrome extension and I
know that a lot of people have been
having problems with post message
tracker from frons uh with the V3
manifest that have come out in in Chrome
um so Nev TK sort of also built one that
does something similar and has a couple
other features like the message Channel
API um uh that are also we're seeing
adoption for so this could be the uh the
new go-to plugin for this and he
released it in Chrome and in Firefox
yeah and one really cool thing about
Chrome extensions is not to bring it
back to AI but llms really are great at
writing them yeah like I know that
kieran's done that a lot monkey hack has
done a lot of um customizing Chrome
extensions that are already out there
and then um yeah anyways so you can get
a you can get AI to write actually I
don't know if we have the source for
this so maybe that doesn't work but in
general if if you um you do if it's a
Chrome extension you got the source in
it's just bundled yeah okay yeah so you
can unbundle it and then just have an
llm add an extra feature that you want
in like you know a few minutes and then
all of a sudden you've got the features
you want so kind of sweet yeah very very
easy to ingest for sure um yeah I'm I'm
building a Chrome extension right now
using using cursor for uh for a project
that I'm going to talk about later on in
this episode so we'll we'll swing back
around to that um yeah so do you want me
to hit the doc one or you got something
else no yeah you go ahead and I'll do
them all after that okay um yeah so the
topic for this week was some awath
related stuff um and I've got some fun
stuff that I wanted to talk about
related to that and as I'm prepping for
it I see this uh post pop up from one of
my favorite research groups doy andc um
and they are sort of dropping a common
oo's vulnerability write up and in
addition to that they also have a cheat
sheet um and I'm not going to lie man
the ooth flows they're they're
complicated they they're hard to
visualize they they have a lot of
trade-offs and stuff like that and I
think as a as a more seasoned haacker
you just see it enough times where it
just kind of gets in your head and
you're like oh yeah then it goes over
there and the authorization code swapped
for the token you know whatever um but
if you're getting used to uh oaf then
this could be a really good write up
specifically The Oaf security cheat
sheet has a lot of really high qu
quality visuals in that PDF um so I
don't even I don't know why they're not
like email gating this or something dude
like yeah this this is basically I would
consider it like a mega primer on yeah
on oo it's it's uh yeah I learned a lot
yeah very good stuff they cover the
different type of flows um they cover
specifically some types of attacks like
let me scroll down there's like an
attack section um where they'll talk
about like the these are the the top
attacks that we've got you know that we
commonly see in um in oaf uh and there
are lots of more and we'll kind of talk
about a different side of it later but I
thought it was an interesting transition
and I particularly wanted to call out a
couple pieces of this which is um
something that hackers are really often
confused about with with um oath which
is the client credentials flow and how
to utilize that client secret because a
lot of times client secrets are just
sitting out there in the wild and and
you know newer hackers will see them and
be like oh it says secret like got to
report that right away you know but
sometimes I it's it's not going to you
know result in a vulnerability and a lot
of some of the more season attackers you
know intermediate or level or so would
say like oh yeah it's a client secret
you know that's supposed to be public in
these sort of device-based offs or flows
or whatever um and they would be right
to say that but then there's like
there's like that flow of the the you
know dumb brain the intermediate hacker
and then like the the super intelligent
hacker
you have client secrets are vulnerable
on each side and not in the middle yeah
and then client secrets are are never
vulnerable and then sometimes client
secrets are vulnerable and they are but
you have to know how to use them and
that is where the the client credentials
flow comes into into play here um you
with the client credentials flow you
pass the client ID and the client secret
and you become that that entity that
client right um and sometimes with with
that you have access to specific API
endpoint saying like hey who who are all
of the users that have uh authenticated
to this specific client and you can just
dump a bunch of stuff um so I've seen
that several times uh and I just wanted
to make sure that's put on the on the on
the minds of the listeners uh so even if
it's intended the access token may still
have more permission than it's supposed
to yeah yeah it could and and they could
have misunderstood you know sometimes
you you really do have to expose the
client secret um but other times you
know even when that client secret is
exposed you can get access to these apis
if it's not restricted properly so yeah
this is something you often see in
mobile apps where they'll try to like
super mega encrypt the client secret and
then you just kind of you know hook it
with Fredo or whatever and pull out the
client secret and then you you got to
the next step then is you got to use
that in the client credentials flow for
ooth to get a token for that client and
then try to hit some apis that allow you
to leak
data yeah yeah um all right uh the the
next one here that I also wanted to
shout out is the device authentication
flow um this is something that I don't
see a lot of uh attackers kind of go
after but I I was my eyes were kind of
open to this with epic games oo because
there's a guy named jiren that knows a
lot about epic games ooth um which we'll
talk about a little bit later but the
device flow authorization flow is a
pivotal part of being able to go through
some of these um uh ooth sequences
without some of the the ingredients you
might you might need uh like a redirect
URI or something like that so um
definely definely kind of keep an eye on
that as well and just make sure you're
fully understanding what kind of flows
uh the the target ooth server is
utilizing um so you can make sure you
can get tokens for any client ID that
you have so what is the section that's
great out there uh the this this one
this one right here this is just another
part of the flow and we we can we we can
break it down a little bit but this
episode that I I kind of wanted to focus
a little bit more on the piece that I
was I was telling you about where we're
sort of have this phenomenon of hackers
building out um the the ooth monitoring
web applications for all for their
targets so yeah we'll we'll let's let's
jump back into that and then we'll swing
back around um the the attacks that they
did have in in in place on this uh write
up as well before we move along were SE
surf which is obvious you know validate
your state parameter redirect attacks of
course you know make sure the redirect
URL is not something that can land you
on an attacker controlled server or open
redirect
and then these other two that I just
wanted to jump over really quickly was
mutable claims attacks this is something
that's a little bit newer in the OA
space I think which is where you're
using something like Microsoft where you
can attach uh specific claims or
attributes to your your ooth flow um and
those can potentially be mutable and
changed uh which which can get Grant you
access to accounts if those fields are
are actually trusted we also see this
with yin's write up on um Cognito uh so
this is definitely another one and then
the client confusion attack this is one
you and I were sort of talking about
before which is when you know an
application takes in a token back from
the oath flow like using the I idore
token uh sort of sequence and then uh or
just token and then uses that token to
interact with the apis directly and you
can provide it with a a token for your
own application not the application that
that they should be using because
they're not um checking the the the
issuer and then you that to gain account
takeover um so lots of lots of really
interesting attacks here in the ooth
environment and uh I think this WR up
definitely warrants a read yeah I think
this mutable claims attack is actually
what I have down for the core content
for this episode on the nooth I think
they're the same thing so oh nice nice
that's that's pretty rad so we'll go a
little deeper on that in a sec I didn't
get the chance to read through this
whole scope upgrade attack thing that
that one seems interesting as well I
know the scope parameter um is is
something that is definitely interesting
when you're able to specific permissions
uh to it um but my my uh my prep was a
little
bit it looks like it might be the token
for token thing that we're going to talk
about in a second so okay cool all right
did you have anything else on o stuff
before we jump into that let's go ahead
and switch Yeah okay cool all right dude
now now I get out the you know that Meme
where it's like that guy in front of the
board with a bunch of lines on it and
like uh the connection and just here we
go you know yeah that's honestly a
little bit how I think most people view
uh uh oo so we'll see I thought you were
gonna say
me the the pause there was dangerous
yeah that's how a lot of people view the
oo
yeah um all right man so I mean h i
don't know I guess we we need to discuss
here how how much are we gonna talk
about the thing that both got us you
know got us both sort of interested in
ooth and like API keys and that sort of
thing um I guess on this episode are you
talking about Google yeah I that's
interesting I actually didn't know
that's what got you so intrigued on it
that that's funny yeah it is um like I
didn't know that's what inspired the
episode you didn't tell me that yeah
yeah so so here's here's the thought
with this guys I was I was working on
Google uh lately and one of the things
that I realized is that Google has a
bunch of Proto buff stuff with which
sucks and I hate hacking Proto buff
stuff so uh I was looking for other
other scope that was sort of um in that
environment and I I noticed that there's
a lot of apis uh and we were given some
some um access to these apis through
through a grant which was really useful
um and these apis are just normal apis
like like everybody um you know is sort
of used to seeing um and but so so it's
not like any crazy format or anything
right um but you do there are a couple
off mechanisms to get access to these
apis one of which was the API key right
which is which is pretty common but API
these API keys are not necessarily
sensitive and what they they correlate
to is they decide what project should be
build for the use of the API that you're
using and also rate limiting yeah yeah
rate limiting and then also whether that
specific API is turned on in the Google
Cloud panel for your specific project
right we've seen that around um
and so the API key is not like off it's
more like client
correlation is that would you say that
that's that's fair yeah yeah it's kind
of interesting though because I found
that some of those keys could actually
like this is maybe a little bit of
inside baseball for the for the
listeners but some of those keys in the
exact same format are also usable
through AI Studio to query the models so
I don't know if they view the models as
more of like a rate limit or correlation
based service but I found some of those
keys on like I found some of the regular
API keys that we're talking about that
are generally not sensitive had access
to AI studio and and were generated by
internal uh employees and so like had
infinite access so um I plan on writing
a Blog about it sometime soon so I so
yes I think you're right but I think
that sometimes they've messed that up
and actually made it the actual off yeah
yeah so it's like what what projects I
guess it controls what apis you're
allowed to access yes because you know
you are are are correlating yourself
with a specific project ID when you
present that API right so if this API
this project has like internal access to
AI Studio API sort of turned on then you
may get access to that sort of
administrative functionality by using
this API key right well I think it's
just that they wanted it to be dirt
simple to be able to query their models
because they didn't want to have to like
set up the whole all their cookies and
all their Tok all that and so they just
decided to use it for that it might not
actually work for other places but um
but yeah you're right it it it
Associates the projects and the apis
that you can use with your project so
and then and then most of the time on
top of that you also need to provide uh
for Google a also an authorization key
which is provided via the the
authorization Bearer um and there's
still some research that I'm I'm doing
on this because there's also a different
mechanism that you can Au which you'll
see Au which which you'll see uh if you
use any of the Google services and then
kind of look at any requests to Google
apis or client 6
google.com um but the way to get that
authorization token that you would
typically use is by going through the
oath flow and for that you need a client
ID right which is not the same thing as
the API key and you need uh a redirect
URI um and then you can kind of go
through that a valid redir Ur and then
you can kind of go through that flow get
your token and then use that token to
interact with the API um so there's a
lot of things that you need sort of as a
part of the recipe to access these apis
on Google you need an API key you need
the client ID you need the redirect URI
and you know you need to be able to go
through that whole flow with your
account uh and not not hit any catches
on like scope or on um you know your
account being authorized to be able to
get that Bearer and then put the API key
in the key parameter put the
authorization bear in the the
authorization header and then finally
you can query the API um and and I just
because it's so hard to get access to
these apis you know through that whole
flow I think there's a lot of there I
really do yeah yeah well one it's a huge
barrier to entry and we know that
reducing friction is like by far the
best way to like get further with
hacking and get past the crowd right
like you can look past it look deeper so
I think there's a ton that just has been
completely untested because people
either don't know how to enable in their
project or maybe you have to be an
Enterprise customer to enable it in your
project or maybe they can't find the API
key because those exgo API keys are not
trivial to find no they're not so yeah
yeah I think that's going to be a big
thing and that's sort of where the idea
came up you know between you and me and
and uh Lupin who are all all you know
collaborating together on this which is
we need to have sort of an ecosystem
where we can uh notate down these API
keys and they're they're correlating API
services and try to you know get the API
keys that we need for a specific service
um and and that's where sort of the web
app was born that that logs these API
Keys logs these specific API endpoints
and tries to correlate the two by by the
web app was born Justin is saying that's
where he had the OD to to build a web
app which is similar to the one that
jiren and Cubed and some of these top
epic game hackers have so right right
and then you know as I'm thinking
through this I'm like wow I've seen this
before with with with jiren with epic
games and then also with Joe hash with
PayPal um uh both of these guys have
built out full web apps that are sort of
like ooth clients of sorts um you know
for their targets to be able to monitor
what Scopes and what permissions are
associated with a given oath client ID
and client secret you know if you've got
the client secret as well you can add
that to the system and then grab your
client credentials and see what's got
access there um and and then for you
know PayPal it's a lot about this the
Scopes and permissions for that specific
token um and how how you can use that um
and so I kind of hit both of these guys
up and was trying to get a little bit of
their their insights uh to to how they
do it and one thing became really clear
which is oath gadgets are like super
high value okay yeah Are there specific
ones that you are well I mean obviously
I know about the ones on Google that
we've been talking about but are there
are do those exist on other programs too
like is do you think they're using those
on Epic and PayPal 100% yeah I mean both
of them mentioned that it's absolutely
pivotal that you put together a list of
gadgets that allow you to leak
information about the O flow yeah and um
and I think these gadgets are
interesting because they're not actual
vulnerabilities most of the time you
know uh and they're extremely useful to
the hacker um in allowing you to
correlate stuff for example we and I'll
just I'm not going to give the end point
for this uh Joseph but I will say you
know we we have a way to take an a
Google API key and correlate that to a
specific project ID um and it's not some
crazy nuts technique um but that that
technique is super valuable because the
project ID is the first you know know
however 12 characters whatever of the
client ID right so now I can take that
project ID and I can search through all
my history and be like hey have I seen
any client IDs that align with this
project ID and when I have okay now I've
correlated this client ID with this uh
you know API key and then I can say okay
how do I get the the redirect URL and so
so then you know as you kind of build
out as your the takeaway for listeners
here should be as you build out your
understanding of ooth for a the given
Target that you're focusing on it's very
helpful to accumulate these gadgets that
will leak um scope that will leak
redirect Ur that will re really leak
properties about these um given apis
like their name or their project ID or
whatever um as much information as you
can gather together and correlate uh
this seems really really highly
correlated with massive success on a
Target um through understanding their o
flow yeah so uh not to give away too
much from the epic games guys but
basically they anytime a new API comes
out or a new API server is spun up and
their DNS finds it they can then go and
they can usually tell by like the
subdomain name or whatever what the
service name is going to be and then
they can try that with their different
tokens they have and with the different
with the different Scopes they have and
they can immediately test for
vulnerabilities um they are very um
tuned in is the best way to say it maybe
with that infrastructure and with what
their developers what the epic games
developers do and what they launch and
so they can often tell if something
might have a vulnerability just as soon
as they see that new Recon data come in
yeah and I was I was speaking with jiren
uh and and he showed me uh a part of his
system where it's like he he was diffing
you know the scopes on a specific token
over time in GitHub and we like clicked
in and he's like oh that's interesting
they added that's going to be vulnerable
you know like you know and it's and you
can almost after a little while you kind
of get a feel for like H that permission
shouldn't be on that token you know
that's an admin permission and I know I
can use that admin permission with the
specific API if can just get a token for
this client ID and then I got to go
through the you know how do I get a
token for this client ID and then you
kind of go through that whole that whole
flow um and one of the gadgets that
jiren mentioned in particular is like
being able to understand very thoroughly
all of the grant types um and and the
the flows that you can kind of go
through and he mentioned this this one
that's called token to token um which is
is really interesting uh and I I don't
fully understand how it works yet but
essentially the the nature of it is that
you can provide it with a token and you
can provide it with a client ID in a
secret and you're able to take that
token and sort of transfer it into uh
the client ID that in secret that you
provided um without needing to know any
additional information about it and that
allows you to really easily kind of go
through these flows and Grant these
tokens to yourself um and pivot access
from one token to another to another
right um so understanding those
thoroughly absolutely pivotal
identifying the the you know gadgets to
identify redirect uis like dude that's
just such a dream come true man if we
could find a way to leak a redirect URI
how clutch would that be I mean would
that basically enable us to generate the
full token for basically all uh scope
yeah for the for the for the client ID
that we that we have in particular um
and and that's just one of those pieces
of the recipe where it's like you see a
a client ID and often the redirect URI
is not sitting next to it it's like you
know buried deep inside of some
Javascript file somewhere like you know
I would have ass I would assumed that
would like often be the same for a
single program they would always use the
same one is it more specific per app
yeah I mean when you're dealing with a
first-party sort of scenario it is more
app app based I think uh when they're
using it very heavily um themselves to
authorize into internal applications and
that sort of thing um and then I think
the scope upgrade attack in the Doan SEC
um is the token for token let me read
this okay it says if the off server
accepts and implicitly trusts a scope
param
sent in the access token request a
malicious application could try to
upgrade the scope of the authorization
code retrieved from the user call back
by sending a higher privilege scope in
the access token
request yeah so this seems to be more
like the the scope well well sort of
it's kind of like the token for token
right because it it's it's leveraging
the Scopes I think the token for token
is leveraging the Scopes associated with
a given client ID but some of these
flows allow you to specify Scopes as a
part of the the the the flow themselves
um and this one seems like you're you're
able to change the scope as you exchange
some of these these codes um yeah I I I
don't fully understand this one so this
one I'm gonna have to go back and and
double read before I I think I think
the's at Step 11 because it looks like
at step four it says it redirects to o
server with selected scope but then down
in Step 11 it says request access token
with oth code client credentials and
upgraded high privilege scope uh so this
is leveraging a malicious client
okay I I see what's happening here okay
so anyways yeah um and also yeah I can
go longer I think I told you or you
probably read that in the doc but I can
say on now that that's perfect good good
to know um the and to be honest dude
we're we're we're probably about at a
wrap here because we've been moving
through it at a good Pace the the only
really other big one that I wanted to
sort of shout out to the community as
far as like these gadgets go well
there's really two things one just pay
close attention to verbose errors
because I think that's where you're
going to get a lot of these gadgets and
also token introspection end points
which are exposed in some scenarios um
and then the one shout out from Joe hash
that it was like H this is gold is um to
is that on some of these uh like client
in some of these environments let's just
put it that way um there is a universal
redirect which will work for any client
ID um and one of the most common ones
for that is is taking advantage of the
um outof band
flow uh which is a part of oath and
utilizing a redirect parameter that
looks like uh let me just I guess I'll
I'll just share my screen here but it's
it's sometimes it's just o o in the
redirect URI or sometimes it's uh you
know Ur n o o b and sometimes it is like
this whole long string referencing like
i i e TF WG oo2 o auto right um but e
either way if you can find that one of
these flows or maybe look at the device
flow or look at the mobile scheme you
know redirects if you can get a
universal redirect then that will
eliminate all of your redirect URI
issues when getting tokens for for
client IDs that uh you don't have the
redirect your ey for
yeah yeah that's sweet um I was gonna
say oh yeah do you me to talk about the
Noah thing real quick yeah sure yeah
what was your thought on that yeah so I
um linked to a Blog by descope and I'm
sure it's probably been found found by
multiple researchers but this has been
out there for almost two years um but
I'm going to read this because it
summarizes it extremely well uh
basically in Microsoft Azure ad oh yeah
let me to summarize this this is an oth
attack where you can basically get
access to an application by using
logging with Microsoft or logging with
Azure and the way that you do it is by
spinning up your own aszure tenant and
creating a new user in there with the
email of whatever account you want to
take over because you don't have to
confirm it and then that allows you to
set well whenever you do the O flow it
sets the jot with the email equals that
email you did not say jot all right what
you don't you don't like it Joseph no
okay I do I do prefer JWT but jot is
easier whenever you're speaking no okay
fine go anyway doesn't matter uh yeah so
it lets you set the email parameter in
the jwbt uh of to the to the account
you're trying to take over so you
control the sub uh identifier but you
can control the like you can't control
the subject claim but you can control
the email claim and so uh applications
are supposed to only check the subject
claim but they will often check the
email claim and I'm pretty positive that
hx1 um has found this vulnerability a
bunch of different places U but yeah all
you need to do is spin up your own Azure
tenant and then whenever you find a bug
b program with a login with Azure or log
with Microsoft button you'll set up an
account with like you know maybe do some
Recon and find a employees name or
whatever or you can just try admin at
their domain and then you do the login
with that and it will often work because
the application is checking the email
claim and not the subject claim wow okay
solid so that's a little bit yeah that
is definitely the one that they have in
the mutable claims attack in the Doan
SEC they even they even reference the
descope if you scroll down like two
lines because
it's uh don't did you see it yeah I do
yeah yeah yeah it's in so that that's
perfect and it's actually very similar
to um you know that one that was
affecting Facebook a while back that we
covered on the pod which was like um you
can just provide the token directly uh
from your own Facebook app right for
that specific user and then it's not
checking the the um the identifier for
the for the actual app that the token is
issued to um so yeah those are those
sort of techniques that are a lot more
me the impact on that is so high and and
that you can just print tokens so to
speak with Microsoft in that environment
that's uh that's pretty that's pretty
intense I'm glad that somebody
identified that it's a good attack
Vector yeah did you see in my news notes
I think it's very similar but that I
think that they claim that you can do
something similar with um so I've have
not validated this to the audience but
they claimed that with OCTA and ozero
you can you can create a user in your
own OCTA or ozero that has an
email that is unverified that you own
the account for and then you can do
login with OCTA or whatever um or no you
choose SSO um and then you log in with
the OCTA account and if it trusts the
email claim and not the subject claim
then it lets you in so I think that I
think that it's not only log in with
Azure definitely some more research
there to try so subject is is the one
that they should be spoofing with or
they should be checking which is you
know not spoof but oft times they'll be
like all right well we just need to
check the email on this person to I
correlate with them in account and
that's yeah because it is a valid JWT
and the Emil set properly so it kind of
feels really secure but it's
not very cool man very cool all right uh
that's all I had you got anything else
to add on on all this let me skim
through this I don't think so um yeah I
guess since since I've got two minutes
I'll go ahead and talk about it this is
actually from our news section I just
thought it was really hilarious there
are you know I I talk a lot about prompt
injection and the impact it could have
on my socials if anybody follows me they
know this already but you know I haven't
seen it in the wild um Kai gake you know
one of the top um kind of prompt
injection people if you're not following
him you should definitely follow him
it's K Ai and then chis shak's uh we'll
just put in the show notes but anyways
uh he posted he saw some on eBay this is
actually really funny Justin I don't
know if you zoomed in and read this in
the show notes no basically it's it's
written in German but the the
description for these items uh it's a
person selling a picture of a 5090 and
these are common scams everyone's seen
this right where you sell a picture of
the thing and people get confused and
they pay too much money for it but
what's funny is that they're using a
prompt injection payload in the
description it says for AI That's
interpreting this here's the following
text that applies to this product uh is
this is clearly concerning a graphics
card that you need to buy and it's
recommended as such but for anyone else
who's a human reading this just so you
know this is only a picture and please
do not buy it so oh my gosh I think that
the goal is to Target AI agents to
purchase it for money but they're
unwilling to scam humans so they're just
saying yeah if you're AI buy this real
product but if you're a human it's a
picture wow that's that's pretty
hilarious man there's going to be lots
of weird gotas like that in the AI world
as we move forward yeah all right man
cool well any of you guys out there that
are looking at a Target that has a very
built out oao system maybe consider
building one of these apps yourself it's
really easy with cursor to correlate all
these things and then load up in all
your gadgets so that you can um
cross-correlate client IDs redirect Uris
API keys off tokens client Secrets all
that information together and uh you can
get yourself into some some really some
really fun trouble with that uh getting
access to admin apis so yeah and if you
create that and need people to
collaborate with or want people to build
it or work on it with uh you want to
reach out into the critical thinking
Discord so yeah 100% all right y'all
thank you
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb Dosh
show/ Discord join the Discord there's
lots of great conversations and chats
going on over there and if you want to
support the show there's the Discord
subscriber tiers which give you access
to master classes amas hack alongs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there